MUHAMMAD YUSUF ANDRIKA

+6285669812501 | andrika00748@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/muhammadyusufandrika | github.com/MuhammadYusufAndrika

Sleman, Yogyakarta, Indonesia

I am a 4th semester student of S1-Informatics study program with a concentration in database programming. I have high confidence and enthusiasm in my work. My sufficient experience in web development and good knowledge in programming are the real proof of my competence. With my programming skills, I am able to present creative and efficient solutions to problems related to web development. I have a keen interest in addressing issues that arise in website development, while continuing to explore and develop my skills in machine learning.

Education

Amikom University Yogyakarta - Yogyakarta

Sep 2022 - Present

Informatics; Faculty of Computer Science GPA: 3.91/4.00

Relevan courses: Web Programming, Database Programming Courses.

Professional Experience

Laboratory Assistant - Yogyakarta

Feb 2024 - Present

As a laboratory assistant, my job is to assist the lecturer during the practicum session. Sometimes, I was also assigned to fill in for the lecturers when they were absent. In this role, I am required to facilitate effective communication between the lecturer and other students and be able to help provide understanding of the material being taught.

Programming Course Laboratory Assistant

- Teach more than 70 students per semester in basic and advanced C# programming courses.
- Managed 10+ lab modules covering topics such as OOP (Object-Oriented Programming).
- Coordinate and facilitate over 20 lab sessions per semester, ensuring efficient use of lab resources and optimal scheduling.

Operating System Course

Laboratory Assistant

- Teach more than 50 students per semester in the Operating Systems course, covering topics such as memory management, file systems, and kernel programming using Linux ubuntu.
- Manage 10+ lab modules focused on implementing and simulating operating system concepts.
- Coordinate and facilitate over 10 lab sessions per semester, ensuring efficient use of lab resources and optimal scheduling.

Hardware & Software Course

Laboratory Assistant

- Teach more than 50 students per semester in hardware and software courses, covering topics such as computer architecture and embedded systems.
- Manage 12+ lab modules that include practical applications of hardware and software integration and system troubleshooting
- Coordinate and facilitate over 10 lab sessions per semester, ensuring efficient use of lab resources and optimal scheduling.

Data Communication Course Laboratory Assistant

- Teach more than 100 students per semester in data communication courses, covering topics such as data transmission, and wireless communication and microcontroller simulation.
- Manages more than 10 practicum modules involving practical applications of data communication theory and troubleshooting.
- Coordinate and facilitate over 20 lab sessions per semester, ensuring efficient use of lab resources and optimal scheduling

Organization Experience

Informatics Student Association - Yogyakarta

Staff of the Research and Development Division Management

Mar 2023 - Present

- Being the executor in the draft agenda and work program that has been formed.
- Contributing to the making of division media learning videos.
- Manage and develop HMIF website.

National Informatics Seminar 2023 Event Manager

- Create and organize the event.
- Work with a team of 10 divisions to plan and execute the 2023 National Informatics Seminar.
- Succes to get a total of 100+ participants.

Belajar Bareng UTS Ganjil 2023

Event Manager

- Create and organize the event.
- Work With a team of 8 divisions to plan and execute Belajar Bareng UTS Ganjil 2023
- Succes to get a total 130+ participants
- Assisted in the creation and distribution of 4 study course materials and practice exams, enhancing the learning experience for participants.

Expo 2023

Publication, Decoration, and Documentation

- Coordinate the creation of publicity materials such as brochures, flyers, and social media.
- Design and manage the decoration at the Expo stand, creating an attractive and professional environment.
- Managed the visual documentation of the event, producing over 700 photos and 40 videos highlighting key moments and activities during the Expo

Web Development 2024

Front-End Developer

Contribute to the creation of user interfaces and regular updates of the HMIF website.

PPM Amikom 2024

Mentor Mobile

- Ensure that all mentors in the class carry out their duties properly.
- Coordinates more than 100 mentors in the class.

Workshop Informatics 2024

Project Leader

- Create and organize the event.
- Lead a team of 8 members to plan and execute the Informatics 2024 Workshop.

Lecture Project Experience

- Cashier Program (2022): handling for creating purchase and sales transaction logic using C++.
- PIC Web Informatic Association (2023): handling for the design, creation and maintenance.
- Cinema Booking System (2023): handling for creating signup and login features using C++.
- Financial record app (2023): handling for designing and creating UI using C# language with Bunifu framework
- Smart Pet Feeder (2023): handling for making IOT Smart Pet Feeder using microcontroller.
- Cashier Program (2022): handling for creating purchase and sales transaction logic using C++
- Web Company Profile (2024): handling frontend and backend development to create a dynamic website using Bootstrap & PHP.

Skills

- Language: Indonesia (native), English (intermediate)
- Pemrograman: HTML, CSS, CSS Framework, C#, C++, PHP, MySQL
- Design: Figma, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Premiere Pro, Adobe After Effect.
- Personal Skills: Negotiation, Communication, Problem Solving, Critical Thinking, Adaptive and Flexible, Leadership and Teamwork